# Curriculum Vitae

### Personal Data

Name Tom Runia

Date of Birth 25 July 1990 | Oegstgeest, The Netherlands

Nationality Dutch

Address Science Park 904, Room C3.239, Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Phone +31 6 46206198 Email runia@uva.nl

## Summary

I am currently a 1st year artificial intelligence PhD student at the University of Amsterdam, working with Cees Snoek. The focus of my research is deep learning for video analysis. Our QUVA lab is a collaboration between the UvA and Qualcomm Research.

### Education

2016 – present

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Artificial Intelligence, University of Amsterdam

• Deep learning for video analysis under supervision of Prof. Cees Snoek

2013 – 2015 | Master of Science (MSc) in Computer Science, Delft University of Technology

- Thesis: High-Speed Object Detection, supervised by Prof. Marco Loog (9.0/10)
- Track: Media and Knowledge Engineering (Intelligent Information Processing)
- Grade Point Average: 8.5/10 (Cum Laude)

2011 - 2012

Bridging Program to Computer Science, Delft University of Technology

• 30 ECTs of courses on Computer Science and Software Engineering

2008 - 2011

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Applied Physics, Delft University of Technology

- Thesis: Image Processing Techniques for Automated Cell Counting (8.0/10)
- Minor: Software Design and Implementation
- Grade Point Average: 7.5/10

2002 - 2008

Secondary School: Preparatory Scientific Education (VWO)

- Bonaventura College Leiden, The Netherlands
- Science and Technology complemented with Economics and Biology

## **Professional Experience**

#### 2014 - 2015

#### **Research Intern at TomTom**

Product Lab, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Graduate internship on computer vision and machine learning. My research focused on high-speed object detection for autonomous driving applications. This involved the design and implementation of high-performance computer vision algorithms using C++ and GPU programming (OpenCL).

#### 2013 – 2015

#### **Software Engineer at Tam Tam**

Operational Services, Delft, The Netherlands

Tam Tam is in the top three of full-service internet agencies in The Netherlands. As a back-end developer at the operational services group I worked on some of the larger websites in the country.

#### 2012 - 2013

#### Student Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Research assistant in the Quantitative Imaging group at TU Delft. One of my tasks involved the implementation of image processing algorithms in Java for superresolution microscopy.

#### 2009 – 2010

#### Software Engineer at Innovative Design Delft

Innovative Design Delft is a small company focusing on data management systems and security. During my study, one day a week I worked on various projects as back-end developer.

### Extracurricular Activities

#### 2014

#### Study Trip 'Learning from Silicon Valley'

Study trip to Silicon Valley for ten entrepreneurial minded students of the TU Delft. We performed a number of cases on innovation and entrepreneurship in Silicon Valley in preparation for our visit to California. There was a strict selection procedure and the TU Delft sponsored the entire trip.

### 2012 – 2013

#### **Secretary of the Study Association for Applied Physics**

Full-time board position at the Study Association for Applied Physics (VvTP). For our work the TU Delft rewarded the board members each with a 1 year scholarship. One of my core contributions was the complete renewal and implementation of the member administration system of the association.

## Extracurricular Activities (Continued)

2009 – 2012

### Various committees at the Study Association for Applied Physics

- President of the website committee (Webcie)
- President of the technical committee (E-cie)
- Editor and designer of the quarterly magazine 'De Physicus'

## Computer Skills

Operating Systems Linux, Mac OS, Windows, Android, iOS

Languages C++, Java, Python, C#, Javascript, HTML/CSS, SQL, OpenGL, OpenCL

Scientific Software Matlab, OpenCV, NumPy, iPython, MatplotLib, TeX, SPSS, ImageJ,

TensorFlow, Caffe, Theano, Keras, CUDA

Research Areas Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Image Processing

## Languages

**Dutch** Native Proficiency

**English** Fluent Proficiency

French & German Elementary Proficiency

## Interests and Activities

Cycling, Traveling, Reading, Movies, Electronic Music, Typography, Business & Economics